so now let's talk about how to reduce
the waste how to have fewer than two to
the nth counters and yet have a long
history so we will talk about the
history based predictor with shared
counters so again the motivation for
this is that with nbit history the way
we just seen it we will need two to the
nth counters per entry if we want to do
things the way we've just done them and
we also know that for repeating patterns
only about n counters out of two to the
are really used in reality we're using
about n plus one but basically the
important thing is that we are using the
number of counters that is proportional
to the size of the history but we need
to have two to the end counters because
we don't know which histories will be
important so the idea here is to share
these two bit counters between entries
instead of dedicating two to the nth two
bit counters to each entry we will have
a pool of two bit counters that entries
will then use but it is possible that
different entries with different program
counters and different histories end up
using the same two bit counter so there
is a possibility of conflict but if we
have enough of these two bit counters
because each entry really doesn't need
too many of them usually we will have
very few conflicts